AN IOP HIDES HIMSELF TO CRY
I've taken some big hits,
but I've blacked out before.
Come on! Get up!
Catch your breath,
but don't keep Vlady waiting!
We've seen worse than that guy.
You've beaten tougher foes than him.
I'm doing what I can, Rubi.
That's not enough.
Get back on your feet, please,
and show him who's boss.
He knows how to motivate me.
I can hear what you think.
Had you forgotten we're connected?
I can't talk to myself anymore!
Stop your Iopishness and get up.
There we go. Don't be a drama queen.
Excellent, Daddy's up!
Now we can get back to playing!
Daddy's tired.
It's time for you to go beddy-byes!
No, I don't believe it!
But I know how to do that, too!
Rubi?
Sorry, friend, I'm at my max here.
His is bigger. Good luck.
Okay, we'll make do.
First one to die loses!
For Eva and the children!
The Iop level.
He looks more like a skeleton.
He looks like Ruel.
Except with me,
the fire is in my underwear.
Papa?
Papa!
It's Goultard.
No mistake, that's ol' Goultard.
Look closely.
Since Adamai had the Eliatrope Dofus,
I was wondering about him...
We'll worry later.
We've got a bigger problem.
Can we get by safely?
They made him regress to his avatar form.
The Iop is explaining something to us now?
What's wrong with you?
You're a princess, but he's a god.
Have some respect.
You're venturing further and further.
I wonder who they were...
It looks like they were a family.
Is that what we are? A family?
What's that? Are those tears on your face?
I felt a drop. It's going to rain.
Anyway, Iops don't cry.
And if ever it had to happen,
an Iop would cry in private.
Okay, Master.
As for your first question,
no, we'll never be a family.
I've never told you why I'm here.
This desert wasn't one, not so long ago.
It was a city, an amazingly beautiful one.
But one day, a monster arrived,
horrible...
...violent, indestructible,
ravaged by despair and hatred.
The city was destroyed.
The entire city... dead.
His thirst for blood slaked,
he returned to sanity.
I am not a nice Iop.
My father transferred a curse to me.
I'm here to remind myself.
I don't understand.
The monster, the monster...
...it was me.
We can forget getting by safely, then?
No. You will get by safely.
No, Dally, we'll take him all together.
Listen to my father, Yugo,
He's the boss here!
-You're going with them.
-In your dreams!
Yugo's the boss. We listen to him.
Ow! What are you doing?
You were trying to knock me out.
I'm too old now. You're not strong enough.
This is a family matter.
I must handle it now.
I'll catch up with you.
Trust me. I've got to do this on my own!
Elely, it's like the time
I let you fight that Pandawa.
I trusted you. It's your turn now.
Hurry. We have to rescue Mama and Flopin!
Let's do as the boss said.
Once he's got it, that's it!
-How do we do this?
-We take him by surprise.
Be careful. We'll go ahead.
A new way of saying goodbye?
You crazy youngsters, watch your backside.
I'm the one who does that.
And don't forget, Papa.
An Iop must know how to use his head!
Dream on, little ones...
Here it comes!
Good luck, Papa!
That thing has side effects.
How disrespectful!
Not at all! I know you very well.
Dark Vlad!
Searching for battles worthy of him.
You think you're good enough?
You didn't answer!
Do you think you're good enough?
Does that answer your question?
You don't seem to remember me!
Let me refresh your memory.
You've got this!
I am Sir Percedal of Sadlygrove!
Nice to meet you.
The true Iop god!
So, now the real question is,
are you good enough?
Oh, wow, I've never been hit
like that before,
No way! You cracked my skull!
You just walk up, your arms like that
and you give me a series of head-butts.
It's just wonderful!
No spectators, real shame.
I didn't understand your gods thing,
but who cares?
Because little Goultard,
he feels something for you.
That's it,
a mix of admiration and animosity.
And just a smidgen of hatred, too.
You were a daddy who never
spent much time with Goultard.
Let's just beat each other like Iopheads
before bringing Goultard back.
Yeah, definitely!
That's what I wanted to hear.
Big speeches aren't our thing
in this family.
Not really, no.
Stay focused. The temperature is rising,
that's not good.
Get a grip,
or this is going to be over swiftly.
You shouldn't rush the preliminaries.
That's Papa.
A racket like that means he's fighting.
Have faith. Dally always comes out on top.
But he lost the powers of the Iop god.
He's going to win!
We must trust each other.
That's what he asked us to do.
I... Okay!
You're slipping.
He... He hits hard...
-Quit complaining.
-You're not getting hit!
Ogrest was much worse.
But I was in shape against Ogrest.
No, you had heart.
Now you're not even an Iop.
What are you talking about?
You're no longer the Iop you were.
You were always up to the challenge.
Look at the madman over there.
He's having a real blast.
You're too scared of never seeing
your family again.
As long as that doesn't change,
it's over.
I've taken big hits,
but I've never blacked out.
You're wrong, Ruby.
How's that?
My family isn't making me weaker,
but stronger.
I'll keep going until I find them.
If you say so...
And I'll prove it!
Come on, Dally!
It's all right. Don't worry.
Incredible.
We might have found a way out of here.
That wasn't really a great idea.
Confronting your dark side?
No, breaking the last column.
It's not good!
I'm glad you're here.
Me too, son.
That idiot Dark Vlad's level
just collapsed.
The tower is balanced on my spirit.
It can't collapse completely.
I hope little Elely is all right.
It would be terrible to lose
my future Iop goddess.